[Music]
welcome to B Central launch event 20125
release way
one I will talk in this session about
new feature related to sustainability
about value chain this is one of uh a
few videos related to Value chain and
this one is related to Value chain and
scope 3 automation related to
production okay let's see what we have
related to Value chain let's remind what
we had earlier so earlier uh we
supported only reporting to
sustainability Ledger entry so we we
could report uh officially uh
requirements to specific governments and
authorities and we could use as a source
sustainability journal and from this
wave general journal and also purchase
invoice or credit memo as well so this
is what we uh used earlier but now with
New Wave we enable Absol Ely new
functionality related to Value chain so
what we have there we have
sustainability value entries this is
very similar as we have costing method
earlier for items so now we have similar
functionality with value entries but
this is sustainability value entry so
what is happening when you post document
from purchase purchase document only
item in this moment not item charge
system will collect all this information
about items and we will have
sustainability value entry and then what
whatever we are handling with these
items with the new items with the
transfer orders with assembly order
production order and so on so on we will
increase and we will change uh this
sustainability value uh related to these
items and on the end idea is to have
everything proper in your sales invoices
in this wave we do not have print out
for that but you can find information
about final um gas emissions related to
items you want to sell so I will be
focused in this uh video to production
order or production features so what we
have
there first we need to start with two
default values what we have in a no
purchase we have items and we have work
machine centers in the center so when we
start with items we create uh some uh
emissions carbon equivalent there and
when we create production B materials
system will use all these items
emissions and move to production Billow
materials and then when we create
purchase or production order system will
move all this information from
production Bill materials to production
order components and the same apply for
work machine centers with routing when
we create routing syst will collect
emissions from work machine Center and
then when we create production order
system will collect all this information
from routing to production order
routings so this is how system is
working with default values now what is
important to know it works only with
carbon equivalent so whatever you enter
your purchase documents system will
automatically in a background calculate
to carbon equivalent based on your uh
emissions and emission fee uh
configuration and then that's it you can
just proceed with your production orders
and when you come to production orders
you can post emissions using production
Journal consumption Journal output
Journal so all journals related to
production can be used for posting what
does it mean in consumption you will
post your consumption your items in
output you will get final um emission
related to your finished good in
production Journal you will get
combination both of demo consumption and
output so this is the same as it appli
for items and work machine Center only
you will get new values related to
emissions again one more thing to uh
important to remember calculation will
be done only for items where
replenishment system is not purchase so
if this is a purchase you will get this
information from your purchase invoice
but if this is production order and
assembly order as well system will
calculate uh from your production and
assembly uh
documents what you will get on the end
you will get sustainability value entry
related to in this case to production
documents and what is important to
remember currently we support only
average method so stability value
entries is very similar with value entry
but we are supporting in this wave only
average method
uh in this moment we will wait your
feedback to see what you need so maybe
we will extend in future but for now we
didn't plan okay how you can start first
what do you need to know you need to
start with sustainability setup so if
you want to see default values on item
Emissions on uh uh work machine centers
you need to enable these fields item
emissions work machine center emissions
but this is only to see uh default
values on these cards but if you want to
use them in production uh process you
need to enable this enable value chain
tracking and once when you enable this
value chain tracking you will get this
warning message because this uh value
chain completely functionality is in
public preview in this moment as I
mentioned for example we do not have it
charge so some of features are still
missing so our suggestion will be first
tested in a send box before you start
with
production and what is important because
all documents are related only to
sustainability value entry except one
first document related with purchase uh
docu purchase invoice is related to both
of uh sustainability Ledger entry and
sustainability value entry so if you
didn't enable um this field system will
post only sustainability Ledger entry so
if you want to have posted in value
entry as well you must enable value uh
chain tracking here and now let's look
first one of item cards on this item
card you already have stock uh you
didn't start using a value
sustainability value chain because you
couldn't use it we didn't have it
earlier and now you until you get new
invoice you need to handle with these
documents so when you
look all information are empty so you do
not have emission for carbon for methan
so all emissions are empty what you can
do uh instead of uh waiting first
purchase the voice you can enter manual
information there so you can get all
these default values on your production
Bill materials but what you need to do
if you are enter manual information you
need to run calculate uh carbon
equivalent so when you run it system
will calculate carbon equivalent per
unit based on your emission and emission
fees so this is only if you want to
start working without getting first
purchase invoice but when you start to
work in general you will work only you
will start all the time with the
purchase documents so let's make a look
one already posted purchase invoice so
you will have sustainability account you
will have emissions all related so
everything is here so if you look in the
find entries you will find both
sustainability Ledger entry and
sustainability value entry so if you
open sustainability value entry you will
get information related to these four
items in a purchase process so all of
them they got some carbon equivalent per
unit so far so good we have something we
can start with
then let's move to production Billow
material as I said if you enable this
functionality it will be visible here in
in production B material if you didn't
enable it will be busy as usual you we
will not change anything in your user
experience so only if you want to use
value chain it will show this new field
car equivalent per unit so if you have
enabled yes you will get this
information and I want to remind you as
you are creating for the first time
system cannot update automatically so
you need to um run uh you need to change
the status and to run calculate CO2 e
this is first time when you enabling
after that system will work
automatically so you have information
here and that's it the same applies for
routing if you open routing you will
find a same New Field carbon equivalent
per unit again from your work centers so
let's make a look because I already show
how it's look like in items let's make a
look what we have from work centers if
you open one of work centers you will
find sustainability fast tab in this
sustainability fast tab you can find
default sustainability account and again
three different
emissions so you will see there are
different emissions so you can enter all
of them and again you can run calculate
co2e to get calculated equivalent for
future usage you can run this uh
calculate only for one uh work or work
and machine Center this is the same
applies for both of them or you can run
from the list for all of them without
any filter already predefined so that's
it and now let's switch to release
production order when you open release
production order by default you will
gets their total carbon equivalent empty
because completely line is empty we
didn't refresh but when we run refresh
production order then we will get
already calculated carbon equivalent so
for this line we have completely
calculation everything the same as
you're running uh regular refresh
production order for regular
manufacturing so only what is difference
you will get these two new Fields you
will get sustainability account number
and you will get total carbon equivalent
information for this item this is based
on information we have in a uh
production build materials and routing
so you can change during posting so now
I will not show you all consumption
output in production Jour so I will show
you only how it look like in production
Journal because this is the same applies
to all of them and um I will not explain
production process I will show you only
what you have new here and new is
sustainability account number syst will
copy so you do not need to change
anything you can change if you want but
there is not any necessity to change
because everything is um related to
default values on your items and work
machine centers then you will find uh
carbon equivalent per unit already
calculated and total carbon carbon
equivalent so that's it when you post
system will post and you will get final
total carbon equivalent in your
production order you can uh change the
status to finish and now you can find
new sustainability value entries from
your production order and when you open
you will see everything what is related
to Output to consumption order all these
details what do I want to emphasize you
will get one new column in capacity
Ledger entry where you will get only
sustainability account because all other
informations are here is sustainability
value entries so only this one link to
sustainability value entry with the uh
sustainability account will exist in a
capacity Ledger entry so if we move uh
now to our uh finished good uh what we
wanted to create with this production
order you will find that we have now
disabled all these values because if you
remember from the beginning of session I
mentioned you can enter manually only if
replenishment policy is a purchase so in
this case this is production order so
you cannot enter manually and we have
already calculated carpo equivalent per
unit based on all this calculation in
production
order so this is everything about using
um value chain and scope three
automation related to production order
please watch another videos related to
sustainability especially other ones
related to uh value chain is this is
important to understand completely
functionality how it's working
thank you for watching this video